Well....
Congratulations.
l'm sorry to have bothered you.
Stop it! lt's not funny.
That poor boy.
Fate has a cruel way
of circling around on you.
After all this work to leave Ashton...
...the girl I love was now engaged
to one of its biggest jerks.
There's a time when a man
needs to fight...
...and a time when he needs to accept
that his destiny's lost...
...the ship has sailed,
and that only a fool will continue.
Truth is, I've always been a fool.
There are some fish
that cannot be caught.
세상엔 희한한
물고기들이 있단다
Sandra Templeton, l love you,
and l will marry you!
It's not that they're faster
or stronger than other fish.
특별히 강하거나
빠르지도 않은데
They're just touched
by something extra.
절대 잡히지 않는 녀석들이지
So as you can see, if we apply
these rules to our everyday life...
One such fish was The Beast.
그중 야수라 불린 놈은
...supply and demand
makes much more sense.
Take a look at the next graph, and the
import of this will be even stronger--
And by the time I was born
he was already a legend.
내가 태어났을 때
이미 전설이었단다
He'd passed up more $ 100 lures
than any fish in Alabama.
녀석한텐 백불 짜리
미끼도 소용없었어
Some said that fish was
the ghost of a thief...
사람들은 그놈을 60년전
--for three hours.
익사한
도둑의 유령이라거나
...who'd drowned in that river
60 years before.
Look!
Others claimed he was a dinosaur
left over from the "Cruaceous" Period.
백악기에 살아남은
공룡이라고 했지만
l didn't put any stock into
such speculation or superstition.
난 그런 억측 따윈
믿지 않았다
All l knew was l'd been trying
to catch that fish...
대신, 너만 했을 때부터
...since l was a boy
no bigger than you.
그놈을 잡으려 애썼지
And on the day you were born....
그리고 네가 태어나던 날...
Well, that was the day
l finally caught him.
마침내 그놈을 잡았다
모든 시도를 해봤지
Now, l'd tried everything on it:
Worms, lures, peanut butter,
peanut butter and cheese.
벌레, 가짜 미끼, 땅콩 버터
But on that day l had a revelation:
그러다 계시를 받은거야
-Daffodils!
-They're your favorite flower.
lf that fish was Henry Walls' ghost,
then the usual bait wasn't gonna work.
그게 진짜
도둑의 유령이라면
How did you get so many?
l called everywhere in five states.
l was gonna have to use something
he truly desired.
도둑이 원할만한
미낄 써야 한다는
l told them it was the only way
to get my wife to marry me.
-Your finger?
-Gold.
- 손가락요?
- 금!
You don't even know me.
Now, l tied my ring onto
the strongest line they made...
난 끼고 있던 반지를
l have the rest of my life to find out.
...strong enough to hold up a bridge,
they said, if only for a few minutes.
세상에서 가장 강한 줄에 묶어
Sandra!
lt's Don. Promise you won't hurt him.
And then l cast upriver.
상류로 낚싯대를 던졌다
lf that's what you want, l swear to it.
-Bloom?
-Don.
The Beast jumped up and grabbed it
before it even hit the water.
놈은 반지가 수면에
닿기도 전에
What the hell are you doing?
This is my girl. Mine!
And just as fast,
he snapped clean through that line.
재빨리 뛰어올라
줄을 통째로 끊어버렸단다
l wasn't aware
that she belonged to anyone.
Well, you can see my predicament.
난 당황했지
My wedding ring,
the symbol of fidelity to my wife...
내 아내이자
내 아이 엄마에게 바친
What's the matter?
Are you too scared to fight back?
-...soon to be mother of my child...
-Make him stop.
- 정절의 징표를
- 좀 말리세요
l promised l wouldn't.
물고기 먹이로 뺏겼으니까
...was now lost in the gut
of an uncatchable fish.
Stop it!
What did you do?
Don, stop!
그래서요?
l followed that fish upriver
and downriver.
그놈을 강 위아래로
쫓아갔단다
While I took the beating of a lifetime,
Don Price was ultimately defeated.
This fish, The Beast...
우린 그 야수를
All the physical activity had worsened
a congenital valve defect.
...the whole time we were calling it
a him, when in fact it was a her.
놈이라 불렀습니다
사실은 암컷이었는데도요
Put simply, his heart
wasn't strong enough.
lt was fat with eggs
it was gonna lay any day.
놈은 산란기였고
Now, l was in a situation.
전 곤란해지고 말았습니다
l could gut that fish
and get my wedding ring back...
그놈 창자를 빼내
반지를 되찾자니
...but in doing so l'd be killing the
smartest catfish in the Ashton River.
애쉬톤 강에서 가장 똑똑한 메기가
죽어버릴테니까요
Don! l will never marry you.
Did l want to deprive
my son the chance...
제 아들놈한테도
What?
You mean, you love this guy?
...to catch a fish like this
of his own?
기회를 줘야하지 않겠습니까?
He's almost a stranger,
and l prefer him to you.
그놈과 전...
This ladyfish and l....
-Well, we had the same destiny.
-"We were part of the same equation."
- 부분적으로...
- "정체가 같았습니다"
Now, you may well ask...
같은 운명이었죠
Oh, darling, darling,
it's still your night.
그래도 오늘은
널 위한 날이잖니
...why did it strike so quick on gold
when nothing else would attract it?
그렇게 꿈쩍 않던 놈이
왜 금을 물었을까요?
That was the lesson
l learned that day...
그게 아들이 태어나던 날
...the day my son was born.
제가 배운 교훈이었습니다
Sometimes the only way to catch
an uncatchable woman...
잡히지 않는 여인을 잡을 수 있는
유일한 방법은
As it turned out, Sandra was able to
keep her same date at the chapel.
...is to offer her a wedding ring.
결혼 반지를 주는거란
사실이죠
Only the groom had changed.
l thought you said you didn't
have a church wedding.
We were all set to,
but there was a complication.
What, a father's not allowed
to talk about his son?
애비가 아들 얘기도 못하니?
l'm a footnote in that story, Dad...
전 아버지 모험담의
ls it the medicine
that's making you thirsty?
...the context for your great adventure,
which never happened, incidentally.
들러리일 뿐예요
그리고 아버진
Truth is,
l've been thirsty my whole life.
You were selling novelty products
in Wichita when l was born.
그런 모험하신 적 없고요
Never really known why.
Come on, Will.
Everyone loves that story!
어쨌든 다들 좋아하잖냐!
There was a time when l was 11....
They don't. l don't love that story. Not
anymore. Not after a thousand times!
아무도 안 좋아해요
다들 지겨워한다구요!
You were talking about your wedding.
l didn't forget.
l was just working on a tangent.
l know every punch line, Dad.
l can tell them as well as you can!
하도 들어서
이젠 외울 지경이에요!
제발 아버지가...
You see, most men, they'll tell you
a story straight through.
For one night,
one night in your entire life...
...the universe did not revolve
around Edward Bloom.
lt won't be complicated,
but it won't be interesting, either.
우주의 중심인양
착각하지 마세요
-How can you not understand that?
-l'm sorry to embarrass you.
- 아직도 모르시겠어요?
- 곤란했다면 미안하다
[ Skipped item nr. 53 ]
l like your stories.
And l like you.
You're embarrassing yourself, Dad.
You just don't see it.
곤란한 건 제가 아니라
아버지예요
Well, when you work for the circus,
you don't have a regular address.
So after three years,
there was a lot of undelivered mail.
After that night, I didn't speak
to my father again for three years.
그 날 이후 난 3년간
아버지와 말을 안 했다
During the four weeks
l was in the hospital...
...the postmaster
finally caught up with me.
And it seems that while my heart
belonged to Sandra...
William Bloom, United Press
lnternational. lf l could just--
UPI의 윌리암 블룸 기잡니다
...the rest of my body belonged
to the U.S. government.
We communicated indirectly, I guess.
간접적인 대화는 있었다
In her letters and Christmas cards,
my mother wrote for both of them.
어머니 편지는
아버지 것이기도 했으니까
And when I'd call, she'd say Dad was
out driving or swimming in the pool.
그러나 전화를 걸면 어머닌
늘 아버지가
True to form, we never
talked about not talking.
외출하셨거나
수영 중이라고 하셨다
내가 아버질 닮았단
생각은 없다
A hitch in the Army was up to
three years at that point...
The truth is, I didn't see anything
of myself in my father.
...and having waited three years
just to meet Sandra...
And I don't think he saw anything
of himself in me.
그건 아버지도
마찬가지일 것이다
...l knew l couldn't survive
being away from her that long.
We were like strangers
who knew each other very well.
So l took every hazardous
assignment l could find...
우린 서로를 잘 아는
이방인 같았다
...with the hope of getting
my time down to less than a year.
Go! Go!
In telling the story
of my father's life...
아버지 인생을 얘기할 때
...it's impossible to separate fact
from fiction, the man from the myth.
사실과 허구를 구분하긴
어렵지만
When l was offered
a secret mission...
...to steal the plans for
the Wong Kai Tang power plant...
최선을 다해 아버지 방식으로
얘기하겠다
...l jumped at the chance
to serve my country.
The best I can do
is to tell it the way he told me.
It doesn't always make sense,
and most of it never happened.
결코 일어난적 없는
앞뒤 안 맞는 일들을
Go! Go!
내 반지 내놔!
Give me back my ring!
고마워!
Thank you!
But that's what kind of story this is.
어쨌든
이건 그런 이야기이다
빅 피쉬
His birth would set the pace
for his unlikely life.
아버진 그 출생부터 유별났는데
No longer than most men's,
but larger.
남들보다 훨씬 극적이었다
And as strange as his stories got...
그리고 이런
...the endings were always
the most surprising of all.
이상한 얘긴
항상 끝이 놀라운 법이다
Yes. Yes, he's here.
네, 있어요
lt's your mother.
어머니셔
And what does Dr. Bennett say?
박사님은 뭐래요?
네, 얘기해야죠
No, sure, l'll talk to him.
Yeah, l'll wait.
기다릴게요
lt's bad?
Any of you got needs?
안좋으시대?
Yeah, it's more than they thought.
They're gonna stop chemo.
좀 심각한가 봐
치료를 중단할거래
-You need to go.
-Probably tonight.
- 가봐야지
- 이따 밤에
- 같이 가
- 당신은 안가도 돼
-l'm going with you.
-No, no, no. You shouldn't.
l'm going with you.
나도 갈래
Now, which one's it gonna be?
무슨 얘길 해줄까?
"Monkey in a Barn,"
or "Dog in the Road"?
갇힌 원숭이?
떠돌이 강아지?
The one about the witch.
마녀 얘기요
[ Skipped item nr. 94 ]
Your momma says l can't
tell you that one anymore.
엄마가 그 얘긴 해주지 말래
-You get nightmares.
-But l'm not scared.
- 악몽 꾼다고
- 안 무서워요
Well, neither was l, at first.
나도 처음엔 안 무서웠다
Now, this took place
in the swamp outside of Ashton.
애쉬톤 외곽에
늪지대가 있었는데
Children weren't allowed in the swamp
on account of the snakes, spiders...
애들은 얼씬도 못하게 했지
뱀이나
...and quicksand that would swallow
you up before you could even scream.
거미 같은 것들이
순식간에 덤벼들었거든
There were five of us
out there that night:
하지만 우린 갔었어
Me, Ruthie, Wilbur Freely...
나랑 루스, 윌버 프릴리
...and the Price Brothers,
Don and Zacky.
프라이스 형제인 돈과 잭키
And not one of us knew
what was in store.
아무도 무슨 일이
벌어질지 몰랐단다
It's common knowledge that most
towns of a certain size have a witch...
말썽꾸러기 꼬마나
배회하는 강아질
...if only to eat
misbehaving children...
잡아먹는 마녀 얘긴
...and the occasional puppy
who wanders into her yard.
어디나 있었으니까
Witches use those bones
to cast spells and curses...
마녀들은 주문을 걸때
...and make the land infertile.
뼈를 사용하거든
-ls it true she got a glass eye?
-l heard she got it from gypsies.
- 정말 유리눈일까?
- 집시들한테 얻었대
How could you miss your cue?
You make me look like a fool
out there alone.
-What's a gypsy?
-Your momma's a gypsy.
- 집시가 뭐야?
- 너희 엄마
Your momma's a bitch.
너희 엄만 창녀야
You weren't alone!
You shouldn't swear.
There's ladies present.
숙녀 앞에서 욕하지마
-Shit.
-Damn.
- 웃기네
- 지랄
Who the hell are you?
꺼져
l'm not going to hurt you.
Screw.
Turn off your flashlights.
She'll see you!
불 꺼
마녀가 볼 거야!
Damn right you're not.
Yet of all the witches in Alabama...
GUARD!
알라바마에 사는 마녀들 중
...there was one who was said
to be the most feared.
Tell your men not to bother us!
가장 무서운 마녀는
And close that curtain!
For she had one glass eye which
was said to contain mystical powers.
한쪽 눈이
유리로 돼있었단다
Please, l need your help.
l heard if you look right at it,
you'll see how you're gonna die.
눈을 보면
자기 죽는 모습이 보인대
What makes you think we'll help you?
That's bull-S-H-l-T, that is.
She's not even a real witch.
말도 안 돼,
진짜 마녀도 아니잖아
lf you're so sure, go get that eye.
그럼 네가 가져와 봐
l heard she keeps it in a box on her
night table. Or are you too scared?
책상 위에 있다니까,
너도 무섭지?
Over the next hour, I described
my love for Sandra K. Templeton...
l'll go in right now and get that eye.
당장 가져올게
-Then do it.
-Fine, l will.
- 해봐
- 할께
...and the ordeal that brought me
before them.
-Fine, you do it.
-Fine, l'm doing it.
- 좋아, 해
- 그래, 한다구
As it had always been,
this love was my salvation.
Edward, don't!
하지 마!
It was destined to be.
She'll make soap out of you.
That's what she does.
너도 비누가 될 거야
그 여잔
We put together an elaborate
plan for escape...
She makes soap out of people.
사람을 비누로 만들어
...involving a whaling ship
to Russia...
...a barge to Cuba,
and a small, dirty canoe to Miami.
We all knew it would be dangerous.
And what are we supposed to do
when we get to America?
l can get you bookings.
l know the biggest man
in show business.
Bob Hope?!
Bigger.
Ready?
And so the twins and I
began our arduous journey...
...halfway around the world.
Unfortunately, there was no way
to send a message back to America.
And so it was no surprise
that the Army believed I was dead.
Ma'am, my name is Edward Bloom...
전 에딘데요
...and there's some folks
like to see your eye.
애들이 눈 좀 보여 달래요
No, God!
After four months, Sandra had gotten
over the worst of the nightmares.
-You get The Eye?
-l brought it.
When the phone rang, she didn't think
it was somehow me calling her.
- 눈은?
- 가져왔어
Let's see it.
봐 봐
When a car drove past, she didn't
get up to check out the window.
Whoa, help!
아, 도와 줘!
l saw how l was gonna die.
l was old and l fell.
진짜 보여
난 늙어서 쓰러지는데
l wasn't old at all.
난 늙지도 않았어
자기 죽음을 보는게 어떤건지
생각했어요
l was thinking about death and all.
About seeing how you're gonna die.
l mean, on one hand,
if dying was all you thought about...
그것만 생각한다면
...it could kind of screw you up.
혼란스럽겠지만
l talked with your father last night.
But it could kind of help you,
couldn't it?
한편으론 도움이 될 수도
있을 거예요
Because, everything else,
you'd know you could survive.
어떤 일이 벌어져도
살거라는걸 알잖아요
You never told me
how your parents met.
They met at Auburn.
What about the details?
How they fell in love.
l guess l'm saying l'd like to know.
그러니까... 알고 싶어요
The circus. The war.
You never told me any of that.
That's because most of it
never happened.
But it's romantic.
That's how l go.
그렇군요
-What?
-What, l know better...
...than to argue romance
with a French woman.
Do you love your father?
Everyone loves my father.
He's a very likable guy.
Do you love him?
You have to understand.
Hi, Mom.
엄마
When l was growing up,
he was gone more than he was there.
And l started thinking maybe he's got
this second life somewhere else.
- 박사님 차예요?
- 그래, 아버지랑 위층에 계신다
-ls that Dr. Bennett's car?
-Yes. He's up with your father now.
Another family, another house.
-And how is he?
-Well-- No, l got it.
- 어떠세요?
- 글쎄... 됐다
And he leaves us
and goes to them.
He's impossible. He won't eat.
Because he doesn't eat, he's weaker.
아무 것도 못 드시고
힘들지 뭐, 못 드시니까
Or, or....
Because he's weak,
he doesn't want to eat.
약해지고
약하니까 못 드시고
Or maybe there is no second family.
Maybe he never wanted a family.
-How much time does he have left?
-You don't talk about that.
- 얼마나 사신대요?
- 그런 얘기 마라
Whatever it is, he likes his second life
better and he tells his stories...
Not yet.
아직은 아냐
Will.
...because he can't stand
this boring place.
윌
Dr. Bennett. Oh, it's good to see you.
-But it's not true.
-Well, what's true?
베넷 박사님, 안녕하세요
My wife, Josephine.
제 아내, 조세핀요
He's never told me
a single true thing.
A pleasure.
반가워요
- 7 개월이군
- 낳을 때 까지요!
-You're seven months.
-To the day!
Look, hey....
l know why you like him.
lt's a boy.
아들이에요
l know why everyone likes him.
Try to get him to drink one of these.
He won't, but go ahead and try.
네가 가봐라
싫다 그러셔도 좀 드시게 해
But l need you to tell me
that l'm not crazy.
Oh, you're not.
And l think you should talk to him.
Larry Puckett's Chevrolet
lets the customer do the talking.
Larry Puckett's GM-certified vehicles
are under factory warranty.
And you can save up to 40 percent
off the original MSRP.
-Did l ever tell you about--?
-Yes.
The maple tree and the Buick?
We've heard it.
l know someone who hasn't.
-The--
-Tree fell on the car, spilling the syrup.
Which attracted the flies,
which got stuck to it...
...and flew off with the whole car.
Dad?
아버지?
[ Skipped item nr. 159 ]
But the real story
is how l got the car.
-You see--
-Dad?
Son.
You want some water?
물 드려요?
Can we talk?
l think l'll get started
on these dishes.
l'll help you.
-You are in for a surprise.
-Am l?
- 곧 놀랄 거다
- 제가요?
Having a kid changes everything.
아이가 주는 선물이지
-You know about icebergs, Dad?
-Do l?
There's the diapers and the burping
and the midnight feeding.
기저귀, 트림,
밤중에 우유 먹이기
l saw an iceberg once.
-Did you do any of that?
-No.
- 해보셨어요?
- 아니
They were hauling it down to Texas
for drinking water.
But l hear it's terrible.
끔찍하단 얘기만 들었다
They didn't count on there being
an elephant frozen inside.
Then you spend years trying
to corrupt and mislead this child...
그렇게 수십 년을 키우면서
머릿속에 똥만 가득 채워놓지
-The woolly kind. A mammoth.
-Dad!
...fill its head with nonsense,
and still it turns out perfectly fine.
그래도 별 문제 없으니까
What?
l'm trying to make a metaphor here.
-You think l'm up for it?
-You learned from the best.
- 전 어떨 것 같아요?
- 나만큼만 하면 돼
Well, you shouldn't have started
with a question...
...because people
want to answer questions.
You should've started with,
"The thing about icebergs is...."
반만요, 엄마한텐
Drink half the can.
l'll tell Mom you drank it all.
Okay, okay. The thing about
icebergs is you only see 10 percent.
Everyone wins.
다 드셨다고 할게요
People needn't worry so much.
lt's not my time yet.
걱정 마라
아직 죽을 때 안됐으니까
The other 90 percent is below
the water where you can't see it.
This is not how l go.
And that's...
이렇게 안 죽어
-Really?
-Truly. l saw it in The Eye.
...what it is with you, Dad.
- 그래요?
- 유리 눈에서 봤다
l am only seeing this little bit...
-The old lady by the swamp?
-She was a witch.
- 늪에 사는 노파요?
- 마녀였어
...that sticks above the water.
Oh, you're only seeing down
to my nose? My chin? My--
No, she was old and probably senile.
늙어서 망령난거예요
l saw my death in that eye,
and this isn't how it happens.
Dad, l have no idea who you are...
내가 죽는 걸 봤는데
이렇겐 아냐
...because you've never told me
a single fact.
So how does it happen?
어땠는데요?
l've told you a thousand facts, Will.
That's what l do, l tell stories!
Surprise ending.
Wouldn't want to ruin it for you.
깜짝 놀랄 결말이지
안 가르쳐 줘
You tell...lies, Dad.
Your mother thought
we wouldn't talk again.
네 엄만 우리가 다시
You tell amusing lies.
Stories are what you tell
a 5-year-old at bedtime.
Look at us. We're talking fine.
얘기할 줄 몰랐나봐
We're storytellers, both of us.
They're not elaborate mythologies
that you maintain...
우린 둘 다 얘기꾼인데
l speak mine out,
you write yours down. Same thing.
난 말로하고
넌 글로 쓰니 같은 거지
...when your son is 10 and 15
and 20 and 30.
And l believed you.
Dad....
아버지...
l believed your stories
so much longer than l should have.
l hope to talk about some things
while l'm here.
제가 있는 동안
얘기 좀 해주세요
Then when l realized
everything you said was impossible...
내가 있는 동안이야
You mean while l'm here.
...l felt like a fool
to have trusted you.
l just want to know
the true versions of things:
전 모든 일들의
실상을 알고 싶어요
You're like Santa Claus
and the Easter Bunny.
Just as charming and just as fake.
Events. Stories.
사건들, 이야기들
You think l'm fake.
You.
아버지
Only on the surface, Dad.
But it's all l've ever seen.
Look.
l'm about to have...
Your mother hasn't been
keeping up the pool.
수영장이 엉망이야
...a kid of my own.
lt would kill me
if he went through his whole life...
-lf you wanted to, you could fix it.
-Yeah, l will.
- 한번 손 좀 봐라
- 그럴께요
...never understanding me.
-You know where the chemicals are?
-l did it when you were gone.
- 약품 두는덴 알지?
- 제가 청소했잖아요
lt would kill you, huh?
l was never much for being
at home, Will. Too confining.
난 집에 있는게 싫었다
답답했거든
What do you want, Will?
Who do you want me to be?
Just yourself.
And this here, being stuck in bed....
이렇게 꼼짝 못하고
죽어가는건
Good, bad, everything.
Just show me who you are for once.
Dying is the worst thing
that's ever happened to me.
내 평생 가장 최악의 일이야
l've been nothing but myself
since the day l was born.
-l thought you said you weren't dying.
-l said this isn't how l go.
- 안 죽는다면서요
- 이렇게 죽진 않는다고
And if you can't see that,
it's your failing, not mine!
The last part is much more unusual.
내 마지막은 특별해
Trust me on that.
그것만은 믿어라
Your father decided
that he needed to have an office...
...and, of course, it wouldn't do
to have it in the house.
So....
Dr. Bennett said l have
to stay at home for a week.
박사님이 이번 주 내내
집에 있으래요
You'll know better than me
what's important.
Oh, that's nothing. Once,
l had to stay in bed for three years.
난 3년동안 누워
있던 적도 있었어
-Did you have the chickenpox?
-l wish.
- 수두 때문에요?
- 그랬으면 좋게
What is it?
lt was during the war.
Your father went missing.
They thought he was dead.
Oh, that really happened?
Truth is, no one quite knew
what was wrong.
뭐가 문제였는진 몰라도
Not everything your father says
is a complete fabrication.
Most times a person
grows up gradually...
성장속도가
...while I found myself in a hurry.
지나치게 빨랐거든
l think l'll go check on him.
My muscles and my bones couldn't
keep up with my body's ambition.
근육과 뼈들이
못 쫓아갈 정도였다
l need to lie down for a bit.
Okay, go.
난 3년이란 시간을
침대에서
So I spent the better part
of three years confined to my bed...
...with the encyclopedia being
my only means of exploration.
백과사전만
뒤적이며 보냈지
I had made it all the way to the G's...
그리고 그 속에서
...hoping to find an answer
to my "gigantificationism"...
내 거인병에 대한
답을 찾다가
금붕어에 관한 항목
하나를 발견했어
...when I uncovered an article
about the common goldfish.
After the war, the sons of Alabama
returned home, looking for work.
"작은 그릇에 놓으면
계속 작은 상태지만"
"Kept in a small bowl,
the goldfish will remain small.
With more space...
Each had the advantage over me.
"더 많은 공간을 주면"
...the fish will grow double, triple,
or quadruple its size."
"두 배, 서너 배로도
자랄 것이다"
They were alive,
while I was officially deceased.
It occurred to me then that perhaps
the reason for my growth...
With my prospects few...
이 모든게
내가 더 큰 공간을
...I took a job as a traveling salesman.
It suited me.
지향하기 때문이란 걸
알게 됐지
...was that I was intended
for larger things.
If there was one thing
you can say about Edward Bloom...
After all, a giant man can't have
an ordinary-sized life.
거인은 보통 크기의 삶을
살 수 없거든
...it's that I am a social person.
As soon as my bones had settled
in their adult configuration...
내 뼈가 성인 형태로
자리 잡았을 때
-Congratulations.
-Thank you, sir.
...I set upon my plan to make
a bigger place for myself in Ashton.
난 큰 공간을 만들
계획을 세웠다
I could be gone
for weeks at a time.
But every other Friday,
I put all the money I made...
Tigers, go!
...into an account set aside
for a proper house...
...with a white picket fence.
l'd like a moment of your time
to tell you about my new product...
Edward Bloom!
에드워드 블룸!
...the Handi-matic.
블룸 조경 회사
A few years later, I added
other products and other cities...
...until my territory stretched from
the coast to western Texas.
애쉬톤 고등학교
과학 박람회
Doggy! My doggy!
My doggy's trapped!
내 강아지가 갇혔어요!
Edward?
Edward Bloom!
lt's me, Norther Winslow.
l don't believe it.
난 애쉬톤에서 가장
거대한 사람이었지
I was the biggest thing
Ashton had ever seen.
I was astonished to see the greatest
poet of both Ashton and Spectre...
Until one day, a stranger arrived.
한 이방인이
나타나던 날까지는
...all the way out in Texas.
l want you to know, when you left
Spectre, it opened my eyes.
There was a whole life out there
that l was not living.
So l traveled.
l saw France, Africa,
half of South America.
Every day, a new adventure.
That's my motto.
Calm down. Calm down, everybody.
Calm down. That's enough.
진정하세요!
다들 진정하세요! 알았습니다
That's great, Norther.
l'm happy for you.
What are you doing now?
-Mr. Mayor, he ate an entire corn field.
-He ate my dog.
- 옥수수를 몽땅 먹어치웠소!
- 내 개도요!
l'm robbing this place.
lf you ain't gonna stop him, mayor,
we will.
이젠 우리가 못 참아요!
l won't have mob violence
in this town.
폭력은 용납 못합니다!
All right, everybody down!
Now, has someone tried
talking to him?
대화는 해봤나요?
Hey!
Just slide that over.
-You can't reason with him.
-He's a monster.
- 할 수가 없어요!
- 괴물이에요!
l'll do it.
제가하죠
-Would you mind grabbing that?
-What?
The gun.
l'm gonna be cleaning out
the cash drawers...
...and my associate here
is gonna handle the vault.
l'll talk to him.
See if l can get him to go.
여길 떠나라고 할게요
That creature could crush you
without trying.
자네가 다칠 수도 있어
Oh, trust me, he'll have to try.
저도 호락호락하진 않습니다
All right, you!
You help my friend, okay?
Let's go!
l'm sorry, ma'am.
l am.
l really just don't want anyone
to get hurt.
lt's not that.
Hello?
이봐요
lt's just....
난 에드워듭니다
얘기 좀 해요!
My name is Edward Bloom,
and l wanna talk to you!
There's no money.
Go away!
돌아가!
We're completely bankrupt.
Don't tell anybody.
Now, l'm not going anywhere
until you show yourself!
당신이 나올때까진
안 갈거요!
It turned out that the Savings & Loan
had already been robbed...
l said, go away!
돌아가라니까!
...not by armed bandits, but
by speculators in Texas real estate.
All right, let's go!
Norther!
Armed with the foreknowledge
of my own death...
내가 본 죽음의 장소가
...I knew the giant couldn't kill me.
거긴 아니었지만
All the same, I preferred to keep
my bones unbroken.
그래도 뼈가 부서지는건
싫었단다
Why are you here?
왜 온거야?
날 먹으라고요
So you can eat me.
The town decided to send
a human sacrifice and l volunteered.
우리 마을이 바치는
제물로 왔소
Yeah! There's gotta be
close to $400 here!
팔은 근육뿐이지만
다린 먹을 만 할거요
My arms are a little stringy, but
there's some good eating in my legs.
And that's just from the drawers.
l mean, l'd be tempted
to eat them myself.
내 다린 나도
먹고싶을 정도니까
Let's see what you got
from the vault.
So l guess, well....
그러니
lf you'd just get it over with quick,
because l'm not much for pain, really.
되도록이면 빨리 끝내줘요
고통스럽지 않게
This is it? The whole vault?
l'm afraid so.
lt's got your deposit slip on it.
Well, l just didn't want you
leaving empty-handed.
Oh, come on! l can't go back!
l'm a human sacrifice!
어차피 난 제물이라
못 돌아가요!
There's something you should know.
The reason they don't have money....
내가 돌아가면 사람들이
lf l go back,
they'll think l'm a coward.
I told Norther about
the vagaries of Texas oil money...
l'd rather be dinner than a coward.
날 겁쟁이라고 할거요
...and its effect on real-estate prices...
Here.
자요
You can start with my hand.
lt'll be an appetizer.
애피타이저로
손부터 먹어요
...and how lax enforcement
of fiduciary process...
l don't want to eat you.
l don't want to eat anybody.
싫어, 아무도 안 먹어
...had made savings and loans
particularly vulnerable.
l just get so hungry.
l'm just too big.
난 그냥 배가 고픈거야
워낙 크니까
Hearing this news,
Norther was left with one conclusion;
Did you ever think that
maybe you're not too big...
l should go to Wall Street.
That's where all the money is.
당신이 큰게 아니라
마을이 작은 거라고
...but maybe this town
is just too small?
생각해 본 적은 없소?
I knew then that while my days
as a criminal were over...
l've heard in real cities
there are buildings so tall...
진짜 도시는
건물들이 아주 커서
Thanks for the hand!
...you can't even see
the tops of them.
꼭대기가 안보인대요
...Norther's were just beginning.
-Really?
-Oh, l wouldn't lie to you.
When Norther made
his first million dollars...
- 정말?
- 거짓말 안해요
And all-you-can-eat buffets.
...he sent me a check for 10,000.
게다가 뷔페도 있어요
-Now, you can eat a lot, can't you?
-l can.
- 많이 먹을 수 있죠?
- 그럼
I protested, but he said it was my fee
as his career advisor.
So why are you wasting your time
in a small town?
근데 왜 이런 작은
마을에 있어요?
It was enough to buy my wife
a proper house...
You're a big man.
You should be in a big city.
큰 사람이면
큰 도시에 있어야지
...with a white picket fence.
You're just trying to get me
to leave, aren't you?
날 내쫓으려고 하는군
And for that, it was all the riches
a man could ever want.
-What's your name, giant?
-Karl.
- 이름이 뭐요?
- 칼
Well, mine's Edward.
And truthfully....
난 에드워드요,
진심으로...
Well, l do want you to leave, Karl.
But l want to leave with you.
당신이 떠나길 바래요
나랑 같이 갑시다
l mean, you think this town
is too small for you?
여기가 너무 작단
생각 안해요?
Well, it's too small for a man
of my ambition.
나 같은 남자한테도 작은데
So, what do you say? Join me?
어쩔래요? 같이 가겠소?
Okay.
좋아
좋아요
Now, first, we gotta
get you ready for the city.
그럼 도시에 어울릴
준비를 합시다
l was drying out.
l see.
l think we ought to get you
a plant mister...
...so we can just spray you
like a fern.
Edward Bloom, first son of Ashton...
에드워드 블룸
자랑스런 애쉬톤의 아들...
...it's with a heavy heart
that we see you go.
자네를 보내는 마음은 무겁지만
But take with you
this key to the city...
우리의 문은 항상 열려 있으니
...and know that any time
you want to come back...
언제든
돌아오고 싶을 때를 위해
...all our doors are open to you.
이 열쇠를 가져가게
That afternoon as I left Ashton,
everyone seemed to have advice.
애쉬톤을 떠나던 날
모두가 충고했지
Come, now.
Find yourself a nice girl, now!
좋은 여자 만나!
Watch your pride, Edward Bloom!
자존심을 지켜, 에드워드!
l don't think l'll ever dry out.
But there was one person whose
counsel I held above all others.
하지만 가장 소중한 충고는
따로 있었어
She said that the biggest fish
in the river...
큰 고기는 안 잡히기 때문에
자기 길을 갈 수 있다는 말
...gets that way
by never being caught.
-What'd she say?
-Beats me.
- 뭐래?
- 몰라
[ Skipped item nr. 286 ]
길은 두 갈래였다
There were two roads out of Ashton;
포장된 새 길과, 오래된 길
A new one which was paved
and an older one that wasn't.
People didn't use
the old one anymore...
오래된 길은
...and it had developed a reputation
for being haunted.
귀신이 다닌다는 소문이
자자했지
Well, since I had no intention
of ever returning to Ashton...
어쨌든 뭐가 있는지
알아보기엔
...this seemed as good a time as any
to find out what lay down that old one.
더할 나위 없이
좋은 기회였단다
-You know anyone who's taken it?
-That poet, Norther Winslow, did.
- 지나간 사람은 있어?
- 시인 노더 윈슬로우
He was going to Paris, France.
파리로 갔다는데
You carry on. l'll see....
l guess he liked it.
No one ever heard from him again.
어떻게 됐는진 아무도 몰라
l'll tell you what.
You go the other way.
따로 가자
l'll cut through here,
and l'll meet you on the far side.
난 숲을 통과할테니
반대편에서 만나자고
Hello.
-Are you Jennifer Hill?
-l am.
You're just trying to run away,
aren't you?
도망칠 속셈이군
And you're Will.
Here.
여기
l've seen a picture of you.
That's how l recognize you.
Just to be sure, you can take my pack.
못 믿겠으면 내 가방 가져가
Listen, Kenny,
why don't we skip the lesson today?
We can go again next week.
Do l have to give it back to my mom?
Well, l won't tell her if you won't.
How did you know my father?
Well, this was on his sales route...
...so he was through here all the time,
and everyone in town knew him.
Were you having an affair?
Wow. Wow, you just said it.
l was expecting to dance
around this for another half-hour.
Why, you son of a--
이 빌어먹을...
l've seen him with women.
He flirts. He always has.
And on some level,
l just presumed that he was...
...cheating on my mom.
l just never had proof.
Well, can l ask you a question?
lf you found this deed,
why didn't you just ask Eddie?
Because he's dying.
분별있는 사람이란
자기 실수를
Now, there comes a point
when a reasonable man...
...will swallow his pride and admit
that he's made a terrible mistake.
경고: 점핑거미
인정하는 사람이란다
Look, l don't know how much
you want to know about any of this.
The truth is,
I was never a reasonable man.
문젠...난 그런 사람이
아니었단 거지
You have one image of your father...
And what I recall of
Sunday school was that...
어릴 때를 돌아보면
...and it'd be wrong of me
to change it...
...the more difficult something is,
the more rewarding it is in the end.
어려운 일일수록
보람이 컸던 것 같아
...especially this late in the game.
My father talked about things
he never did...
...and l'm sure he did a lot of things
that he never talked about.
l'm just trying to reconcile the two.
The first thing
you have to understand...
...is that your father
never meant to end up here.
Yet he did.
Twice.
The first time, he was early.
The second time, he was late.
Those days, your father was working
for himself.
If there's one thing you could
say about Edward Bloom...
...it's that he was a social person,
and people took a liking to him.
One night, he was returning
from three weeks on the road...
...when he hit a thunderstorm
unlike any in his life.
Friend! Welcome to you!
어서 와요! 잘 오셨소!
-What's your name?
-Edward Bloom.
- 이름이 뭐죠?
- 에드워드 블룸
-"Bloom" like a flower?
-Yes.
"꽃 핀다"의 블룸?
Oh, here! Here you are, right here.
"Edward Bloom."
여깄네요!
에드워드 블룸
We weren't expecting you yet.
아직 올 때가 아닌데
-You were expecting me?
-Not yet.
- 절 기다렸나요?
- 아직은요
-You must've taken a shortcut.
-Why, yes, l did. lt almost killed me.
- 지름길로 왔군요
- 맞아요, 거의 죽을뻔 했죠
Life will do that to you.
And truthfully, the long way is easier.
삶이란 게 그래요
먼 길이 더 쉬울 때가 있지
-But it's longer.
-Much longer.
- 오래 걸리지만
- 훨씬 오래
And you're here now,
and that's what matters.
어쨌든 왔잖소
What is this place?
여기가 어디죠?
The town of Spectre.
Best-kept secret in Alabama!
유령 마을이요
아주 비밀스런 곳이지!
Now, it says here
you're from Ashton, right?
목록을 보니
애쉬톤에서 오셨군
Last person we had from Ashton
was Norther Winslow.
거기선 윈슬로우가
마지막이었소
The poet?
Whatever happened to him?
그 시인요?
어디로 갔죠?
He's still here. Let me buy you a drink.
l'll tell you all about it.
아직 있어요
어쨌든 한잔하면서 얘기합시다
윈슬로우도 부르고
Hell, l'll have him tell you!
l have to meet somebody,
and l'm already running late.
약속이 있는데 벌써 늦었어요
Now, son, l already told you.
You're early.
아까 말했잖소
당신은 일찍 왔다고
Fate has a way of circling back
on a man...
...and taking him by surprise.
Now, tell me if that isn't
the best pie you ever ate.
당신이 먹어본 것 중
최고일거요
그렇네요
lt truly is.
A man sees things differently
at different times in his life.
Well, everything tastes better here.
Even the water is sweet.
여긴 모든게 맛이 좋아요
물조차 달죠
This town didn't seem the same
now that he was older.
A new road had brought
the outside world to Spectre...
Never gets too hot,
too cold, too humid.
덥지도, 춥지도,
눅눅하지도 않고
...and with it, banks, liens and debt.
At night, the wind goes through
the trees where you'd swear...
밤에 나무에서 부는 바람은
Almost everywhere you looked,
people were bankrupt.
...there was a whole symphony
out there playing just for you.
완벽한 교향곡처럼 들려요
The auction today
is for the town of Spectre.
Hey! Jenny!
제니!
-The opening bid will be $ 10,000.
-So Edward Bloom...
이리 줘!
Come back here!
-...decided to buy the town.
-50,000.
Jenny!
제니!
-l couldn't believe my eyes--
-He was never a wealthy man...
...but he had made other men rich,
and now he asked for their favors.
-l'm trying to save....
-Most of them hadn't seen Spectre.
They only had Edward's words
to describe it.
Hey, l need those.
난 신발이 필요해!
-There is no softer ground than town.
-That almost rhymes.
That's all he needed.
He sold them on the dream.
- 솜털 같은 대지예요
- 시적이네요
He's our poet laureate. Come on.
So first he bought the farms.
명색이 시인이잖소
갑시다
Then he bought the houses.
And then he bought the stores.
I agreed to spend the afternoon,
if only to understand...
낯설면서도 친숙한
그곳의 정체가
Whatever he bought, the people were
not asked to leave or pay rent.
궁금해진 난
잠깐 머물기로 했다
...the mystery of how a place could
feel so strange and yet so familiar.
They were just asked to keep
doing as they were doing.
In that way, he could make sure
the town would never die.
l've been working on this poem
for 12 years.
난 12년간
이 시를 쓰고 있소
Really?
그래요?
Within six months, his trust had
purchased the entire town.
There's a lot of expectation.
l don't wanna disappoint my fans.
팬들의 기대가 커요
실망시키면 안되지
With one exception.
May l?
봐도 돼요?
아주 짙은 잔디,
아주 파란 하늘
유령은 정말 멋지다!
lt's only three lines long.
딱 3행이네요
You must be Edward Bloom.
This is why you should never show
a work in progress.
이래서 중간에 보여 주면
안 된다니까!
How do you know?
No one would come out here
unless they had business.
And no one would have business
with me except for you.
You're buying the town.
Apparently l overlooked this one
piece of it, and l'd like to remedy that.
ln order for the town to be preserved,
the trust must own it, in its entirety.
And so l've heard.
l'll offer you more than it's worth.
And you won't have to move.
Nothing will change except the name
on the deed, you have my word.
Now, let me get this straight.
You buy the swamp from me,
but l'll stay in it?
You'll own the house,
but it'll still be mine?
l'll be here, and you'll come and go as
you please to one place or another.
Do l have that right?
ln so many words, yes.
Yeah, then l don't think so,
Mr. Bloom.
lf nothing's gonna change,
l'd just as soon it not change...
...in the way things haven't been
changing all this time.
l got him!
잡았어요!
lt's not like you'll lose anything.
You can ask anyone in town.
Why are you buying this land,
Mr. Bloom?
Some sort of midlife crisis?
lnstead of buying a convertible,
you buy a town?
Helping people makes me happy.
There's leeches in there.
거머리 있어요
l'm not convinced
you should be happy.
-Did you see that woman?
-What did she look like?
- 그 여자 봤니?
- 어떤 여자요?
-l'm sorry. Have l offended you?
-No.
-Well, she was....
-Was she naked?
- 그게...
- 벗고 있었어요?
You did exactly what you promised.
You came back.
l was just expecting you sooner.
Yes, she was.
그래
lt's not a woman. lt's a fish.
No one ever catches her.
여자가 아니라 물고기예요
아무도 못 잡죠
사람들마다 보는
모습이 달라요
Fish looks different
to different people.
My daddy said it looked like the
coon dog he had when he was a kid...
우리 아빤
너구리 사냥개랑
You're Beamen's daughter.
닮았다고 했어요
...back from the dead.
Your name's different.
Did you get married?
l was 18. He was 28.
Turns out that was a big difference.
Oh, darn.
제길!
-How old are you?
-Eighteen.
- 몇 살이에요?
- 열 여덟
l'm 8. That means when l'm 18,
you'll be 28.
난 8살 이니, 내가 18살이면
아저씬 28살이에요
-And when l'm 28, you'll only be 38.
-You're pretty good at arithmetic.
- 내가 28살에, 아저씬 38살
- 산수 잘하네
l won't be selling you this house,
Mr. Bloom.
And when l'm 38, you'll be 48.
That's not much difference at all.
내가 38에 아저씬 48
별 차이 없어요
l see.
Sure is a lot now, though, huh?
지금은 많은거야
Well, thank you for your time.
-lt's stuck.
-Yeah.
-Oh, l'm so sorry! l--
-lt's okay. Just leave it.
-No, l'll--
-Please! Just go.
-But--
-Go.
Hey, Edward!
에드워드!
Most men in that situation would
accept their failure and move on.
[ Skipped item nr. 362 ]
But Edward was not like most men.
[ Skipped item nr. 363 ]
Roses are red
Violets are blue
장미는 빨갛고
제비꽃은 파랗다
난 유령 마을을 사랑해...
I love Spectre....
Hold!
Excuse me.
실례
They both had completely
different characters but...
...well, just one pair of legs.
Jenny thinks you're quite a catch.
We all do.
제니는 당신을
좋은 배우자로 생각해요
What?
네?
l said, you're quite a catch.
결혼 상대요
As the months passed, he found
more and more things to fix...
...until the shack no longer
resembled itself.
l have to leave.
전 떠나야 돼요
Of course, the best part
was coming up with the new material.
Tonight.
오늘밤에
By the time the twins and l
had got to Havana...
Why?
왜죠?
...we'd worked out a new routine,
using only a ukulele and a harmonica.
This town is more than any man
could ask for.
여긴 낙원이에요
And if l were to end up here,
l would consider myself lucky.
이런데서 평생 살 수 있다면
행복하겠지만
But the truth is, l'm just not ready
to end up anywhere.
전 어디에도 정착할 준비가
안 돼 있어요
But no one's ever left.
여길 떠난 사람은 없소!
How are you gonna make it
without your shoes?
신발도 없이
어떻게 떠날 건데요?
Well, l suspect it will hurt. A lot.
발이 아프겠지
아주 많이
Now, l'm sorry, but....
Well, goodbye.
죄송해요, 하지만...
안녕히 계세요
-Well....
-You could leave it there.
-You won't find a better place.
-l don't expect to.
- 더 나은 곳도 없소!
- 기대 안해요
돌아올 거라고 약속해요
Promise me you'll come back.
l promise. Someday.
When l'm really supposed to.
약속할게, 언젠간
정말 돌아와야 할 때
No.
Now, don't.
Don't be embarrassed. l should never
have let you think that....
l'm in love with my wife.
Yeah, l know.
And from the first day l saw her
until the day l die...
...she's the only one.
Lucky girl.
That night,
I reached two conclusions.
그 날밤, 난 두 가지
결론에 다다랐다
l'm sorry, Jenny. l am.
The first was that a dangerous path
is made much worse by darkness.
위험한 길은 어두울수록
더 나빠진단 것과
내가 절망적으로
길을 잃었단 사실
The second was that I was
hopelessly and irrevocably lost.
Wait! Edward.
These woods would become
my graveyard.
그 숲이 내 묘지가
될 수도 있었어
As difficult as it was to reach Spectre,
I was fated to get there eventually.
그렇게 어렵게 들어갔던 만큼
난 결국 돌아갈 운명이었다
After all, no man can avoid
reaching the end of his life.
아무도 자기 삶의 끝을
피할 순 없지
And then I realized
this wasn't the end of my life.
하지만 이게 끝이
아니란 걸 깨달았다
This isn't how l die.
난 이렇게 죽는게 아냐
One day, Edward Bloom left...
...and never returned
to the town he'd saved.
Friend.
친구!
-What happened to your shoes?
-They kind of got ahead of me.
- 신발은?
- 먼저 갔어
As for the girl...
...the common belief
was that she'd become a witch...
...and crazy at that.
She became something
of a legend herself.
And the story ended where it began.
l don't know if you saw it,
but Josephine had some photos...
뉴스위크에
조세핀이 찍은
...in the most recent Newsweek.
사진이 실렸어요
Logically, you couldn't be
the witch, because she was...
Really?
그래?
...old when he was young.
That's just wonderful.
대단하구나
Well, it's logical if you think
like your father.
그것 때문에 일주일을
모로코에 있었어요
l spent a week in Morocco
for the story. lt was incredible.
See, to him there's only
two women:
Oh. We'll have to pick up a copy.
나도 사서 봐야겠는걸
Your mother...
...and everyone else.
And one day...
...l realized l was in love with a man
who could never love me back.
l was living in a fairy tale.
l don't know if you're aware of this,
Josephine...
아프리카산 앵무새들은
l'm not sure l should've told you
any of this.
No, no, no, l wanted to know. l'm....
자기들 고향인 콩고에선
오직 프랑스말만 한단다
...but African parrots, in their native
Congo, they speak only French.
l'm glad l know.
l wanted to be as important to him
as you were.
Really?
정말요?
You're lucky to get four words
out of them in English.
And l'm....
몇 마디라도 영어가 들리면
운 좋은 거야
l was never gonna be.
But if you were to walk
through the jungle...
너도 정글에선
앵무새들의
...you'd hear them speaking
the most elaborate French.
섬세한 프랑스 말을
들을 수 있을게다
l was make-believe.
And his other life, you....
Those parrots talk about everything.
Politics, movies, fashion.
그 앵무새들은 모든걸 얘기하지
정치, 영화, 패션
You were real.
Everything but religion.
종교만 빼고 전부
Why not religion, Dad?
종교는 왜요?
lt's rude to talk about religion. You
never know who you're gonna offend.
누구랑 싸우게 될지
전혀 모르니까
Josephine actually went
to the Congo last year.
조세핀도 작년에
콩고에 갔었어요
Oh, so you know.
그럼 너도 알겠구나!
Mom?
Josephine?
Hello.
안녕
Hi. How are you feeling?
좀 어떠세요?
Oh, l was dreaming.
꿈을 꾸고 있었다
Will!
What were you dreaming about?
무슨 꿈이요?
What happened?
Your father had a stroke.
Oh, l don't usually remember...
특별히 나쁜 꿈 아니면
He's upstairs with your mom
and Dr. Bennett.
...unless they're especially portentous.
Do you know what that word means?
잘 기억 안나
그게 무슨 뜻인지 아니?
ls he gonna be okay?
나쁜 꿈은
실제 일어난다는 거다
lt means when you dream about
something that's gonna happen.
Like one night, l had a dream...
예전에 난
...where this crow came and said:
l don't suppose that l could...
까마귀가 날아와
숙모가 죽을 거라고 말하는
...stay here with him.
l mean, in case....
"Your aunt is gonna die."
꿈을 꾼 적이 있지
ln case he wakes up,
l really ought to be here.
l was so scared,
l woke up my parents...
l'll stay.
아주 무서웠다
부모님을 깨웠지만
Why don't you go home with
Josephine. l'll stay tonight.
...but they said it was just a dream
and to get back to bed.
꿈일 뿐이니
그냥 자라고만 하셨어
-ls that okay?
-Fine.
But the next morning,
my Aunt Stacy was dead.
하지만 다음날 아침
숙모가 돌아가셨다
That's terrible.
끔찍하군요!
Will, you'll call if there's any...?
Terrible for her, but think about me,
young boy with that kind of power.
그런 종류의 힘을 가졌던
내 생각도 한번 해보렴
l will. l will. l'll call.
Wasn't three weeks later when the
crow came back to me in a dream...
3주도 안 돼서
그 까마귀가 다시 나타난 거야
-Do you want some time with Dad?
-Yes. Thank you.
...and said, "Your daddy's gonna die."
이번엔 우리 아버지가
죽을 거라면서
난 속수무책이었다
l didn't know what to do.
l finally told my father, but he said:
아버지한테 말씀드렸더니
"Oh, not to worry."
But l could see he was rattled.
걱정 말라고 하셨지만
평소와 다르게 당황하는 눈치셨어
The next morning, he wasn't himself.
다음날 아침
아버진 뭔가가
Kept looking around, waiting for
something to drop on his head.
떨어지길 기다리듯
계속 두리번거리셨다
Because the crow didn't say how it
was gonna happen, just those words:
까마귀는 아버지가
죽는다고만 했지
"Your daddy's gonna die."
어떻게 죽는지는
말 안 했으니까
Well, he left home early
and was gone a long time.
아버진 밖으로 나가
한참 후에 돌아오셨는데
When he finally came back,
he looked terrible...
하루종일 도끼가 떨어지길
...like he was waiting
for the ax to fall all day.
기다렸던 사람처럼
끔찍해 보이더구나
He said to my mother:
아버지 말씀이
"l've just had the worst day of my life."
최악의 날이었다고 하시자
어머닌
"You think you've had a bad day?"
she said.
당신만 최악은 아니라고
하시는 거야
"This morning, the milkman
dropped dead on the porch."
오늘 아침에 우유 배달부가
죽었다면서
Because, see, my mother
was banging the milkman.
어머닌 그 배달부랑
그렇고 그런 사이였지
Glad to see you're not trying
to have a heartfelt talk.
-Can l take your picture?
-Oh, you don't need a picture.
- 사진 좀 찍어도 되요?
- 사진이 필요 없잖니
One of my greatest
annoyances is when...
...people try to talk to those
who can't hear them.
Just look up the word "handsome"
in the dictionary.
사전에서 핸섬이란
단어만 찾아라
Well, we have an advantage.
Please?
부탁드려요
My father and l never talk.
All right.
알았다
l have photos of the wedding
to show you.
결혼 사진 가져왔어요
Your father ever tell you
about the day you were born?
아버님이 더 멋있던데요
There is a great one
of you and my father.
Yeah, a thousand times.
He caught an uncatchable fish.
Not that. The real story.
He ever tell you that?
l want to see pictures of your wedding.
l've never seen any.
그러고 보니 아버님
결혼 사진을 본적이 없네요
No.
Well, your mother came in about
3 in the afternoon.
That's because we didn't have
a proper wedding.
결혼식이라 할만한게
없었으니까
Her neighbor drove her, on account of
your father was away on business...
Your mother-in-law was
never supposed to marry me.
네 시어머닌 다른 남자랑
...in Wichita.
-She was engaged to somebody else.
-l never knew.
- 약혼한 상태였다
- 몰랐어요
You were born a week early,
but there were no complications.
Will never told you?
윌이 얘기 안 하든?
lt was a perfect delivery.
Your father was sorry not to be there.
Probably just as well.
했어도 다르게 했겠지
He would have told it wrong, anyway.
아예 안 했거나
But it wasn't the custom then for men
to be in the room for deliveries...
All the facts, none of the flavor.
하지만 전부 사실이란다
Oh. So this is a tall tale.
특별한 얘기겠군요
...so l can't see how it would've been
much different had he been there.
Well, it's not a short one.
글쎄... 평범하진 않지
And that's the real story
of how you were born.
[ Skipped item nr. 459 ]
Not very exciting, is it?
서커스
I'd just left Spectre and was
on my way to discover my destiny.
난 유령 마을을 떠나
내 운명을 찾아 나섰다
And l suppose if l had to choose
between the true version...
I'd just left Spectre and was
on my way to discover my destiny.
...and an elaborate one involving
a fish and a wedding ring...
Not knowing what
that would be exactly...
그게 뭔진 정확히 몰랐지만
...I explored every opportunity
that presented itself.
주어진 모든 기회를
받아들였지
...l might choose the fancy version.
But, then that's just me.
l kind of liked your version.
Dad?
포포와 코코였습니다
Coco! Coco! There they are.
Hey, Dad? Hey, you want me
to get the nurse?
Ladies and gentlemen!
여러분! 여러분 중엔
What do you want? What can l do?
What can l get?
You may think
you've seen the unusual.
살면서 유별난걸 보신 분도
계실테고
You want some water?
You want a bit of water?
You may think you've seen the bizarre.
기이한걸 보신 분들도
계실겁니다
The river.
But l've traveled
to the five corners of the world...
하지만 제가 세상의 모든
구석을 여행해본 후
The river?
Tell me how it happens.
...and let me tell you,
l've never seen anything like this!
자신있게 말씀드리건대
지금껏 이런걸 본적은 없었습니다!
How what happens?
How l go.
When l met this man...
이 남잘 만났을때
...he was picking oranges in Florida.
그는 오렌지를 따고
있었습니다
You mean what you saw in The Eye?
His fellow workers called him
El Penumbra. "The Shadow."
그의 동료들은 그를
"엘 페늄브라"...
"그림자"라 불렀죠
Because when you worked
beside him...
그의 곁에서 일할 때면
...he blocked out the daylight!
햇볕이
하나도 안 들었거든요!
Not to alarm you, ma'am,
but if this man wanted to...
맘만 먹으면
여러분의 머리를
l don't know that story, Dad.
You never told me that one.
...he could crush your head
between his toes...
호두알처럼
발가락 사이에 끼고
...like a tiny walnut.
But he won't do it.
Okay. Hey, okay, l'll try.
뭉갤 수도 있겠지만
안심하십시오
l need your help.
Tell me how it starts.
아뇨, 여성분들을
No. No, ladies and gentlemen...
...he will not hurt her...
해치진 않습니다
Like this.
...because he is our own gentle giant.
그는 우리 모두의
다정한 거인이니까요
Okay. Okay.
Ladies and gentlemen,
l give you Colossus!
신사 숙녀 여러분...
콜로서스를 소개합니다!
Okay, so it's in the morning...
...and you and l are in the hospital,
and l've fallen asleep. And l wake up...
...and I see you,
and somehow you're better.
Dad?
You're different.
-Dad.
-Let's get out of here.
Then I say;
Dad, you're in no condition--
Get that wheelchair.
Hurry up! We haven't much time!
Once we get off this floor,
we're in the clear.
And we get in the wheelchair...
-Faster!
-...like we're escaping the hospital.
What are you doing?
We pass Dr. Bennett,
who tries to slow us down.
-Stop them!
-We're flying down the hall.
Orderly after orderly is chasing us.
Mom and Josephine
are at the end.
No time to explain! Stall them!
We come flying out
over the curb...
...and your old red Charger is there.
But it's new. Brand-new.
And l pick you up...
...and somehow you hardly weigh
anything. l can't explain it.
Leave it! We don't need it!
Water. l need water.
-Where are we going?
-The river.
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls...
신사 숙녀 여러분
...thank y'all for coming.
와 주셔서 감사합니다
And we have to take Glenville
to avoid traffic...
모두들 안녕히
돌아가십시오
Drive home safely, everyone.
Thank you for coming.
...because the damn church
people drive too slow.
It was on that night
Karl met his destiny.
칼은 그날 자신의
운명을 만났고
나도 거의 그랬단다
And I met mine, almost.
They say when you meet
the love of your life, time stops.
인생의 사랑을 만나게 되면
시간이 멈춘단 말은
And that's true.
진실이야
And as we get close to the river...
He's here!
...we see that everybody
is already there.
What they don't tell you
is that once time starts again...
그러다 다시 흘러가기
시작하면
...it moves extra fast to catch up.
못 잡을 정도로
빨리 지나가지
And l mean...
...everyone.
lt's unbelievable.
The story of my life.
What's your name?
이름이 뭔가?
- 칼이오
- 칼
-lt's Karl.
-Karl.
The strange thing is, there's
not a sad face to be found.
Tell me, Karl, have you ever heard
the term "involuntary servitude"?
비자발적 노예 상태란 말 아나?
Everyone is just so glad
to see you...
...and send you off right.
-No.
-"Unconscionable contract"?
- 아뇨
- 불공정 계약은?
Goodbye, everybody!
Farewell! Adieu!
-Nope.
-Great.
- 아뇨
- 좋아
Here you go.
이걸 받게
Here you are.
여기
Mr. Soggybottom,
come down this here...
소기바텀 씨
칼이 등에 대고
...so he can use your back
to sign on it.
My girl in the river.
사인 할 수 있게 해줘
그래, 고맙네
Okay. Thank you. Yeah.
Hey, kid.
이봐
-Your friend just made himself a star.
-Oh, that's great.
- 자네 친구는 이제 스타야
- 잘됐군요
- 내 변호사 소기바텀 씨
- 안녕하세요
-My attorney, Mr. Soggybottom.
-Good to meet you.
Pleased to meet you.
반가워요
What's the matter? l haven't
seen a customer so depressed...
왜 그러나?
코끼리 엉덩이에
...since the elephant sat
on that farmer's wife.
깔린 것 같은
우울한 표정이군
"Depressed"?
"우울해?"
See? The big guy likes it.
봤나?
농담을 좋아하는군
l just saw the woman l'm gonna marry.
좀 전에 그 여잘 봤어요
l know it. But l lost her.
결혼할 여잔데 놓쳤다고요
Oh, tough break.
안됐군
Well, most men have to get married
before they lose their wives.
놓친 고기가
더 커 보이는 법이지
l'm gonna spend the rest of my life
looking for her. That or die alone.
내 인생은 그녀를 찾는데 쓸 겁니다
안되면 죽어버릴 거예요
Damn, kid.
저런!
Let me guess. Real pretty?
어디 보자... 예쁜가?
You become what you always were.
Reddish-blondish hair?
붉은 빛의 금발?
A very big fish.
Blue dress?
푸른 드레스?
Yeah!
네!
l know her uncle. Friends of the family.
그 애 삼촌을 알아
가족 친구들도
And that's how it happens.
Who is she? Where does she live?
누구예요? 어디 살죠?
Yeah.
Forget it. Don't waste your time.
She's out of your league.
잊어버려
못 오를 나무야
-What? You don't even know me.
-Sure l do.
- 내가 어때서요
- 촌구석에선
Exactly.
You were hot shit back in Hickville, but
here in the real world, you got squat.
최고지만 진짜 세상에선
아무 것도 아닌 존재지
You don't have a plan or a job.
직업도, 계획도 없고
Nothing except the clothes
on your back.
몸에 걸친 옷 말곤
아무 것도 없잖아
Well, l have a whole backpack
full of clothes.
가방에 옷 많아요
Oh, someone stole my backpack.
누가 훔쳐갔나봐요!
You were a big fish in a small pond,
but this here is the ocean...
자넨 연못에선 대어지만
바다로 가면
...and you're drowning.
Go back to Puddleville.
빠져 죽을 거야
돌아가게
- 그래야 행복해
- 나도 계획이 있어요
-You'll be happy there.
-You say l don't have a plan. l do.
l'll find that girl, marry her,
and spend the rest of my life with her.
그 여자랑 결혼해서
평생 같이 살 거예요
l don't have a job, but l would
have a job if you gave me one.
댁이 일자릴 주면
직업도 생길 거구요
And l may not have much...
가진 건 적지만...
...but l have more determination
than any man you're likely to meet.
결단력 만큼은
누구보다도 뛰어나요
Mom?
l'm sorry, kid. l don't do charity.
Come on, big boy.
난 자선 사업가가 아냐
가자고, 빅 보이
Wait. Look, l'll work
night and day for you...
죽어라 일할게요
돈은 안 주셔도 돼요
...and you won't have to pay me.
You just have to tell me who she is.
그녀가 누군지만
말해주세요
Every month you work for me...
일하는 달마다
...l'll tell you one thing about her.
That's my final offer.
하나씩 얘기해주지
최종 제안일세
Let's get started.
시작하자고
난 그자가 시키는
모든 일을 했단다
From that moment on, I did everything
Mr. Calloway asked.
I'd go three days
without stopping to eat.
안 먹고 안자고,
사흘 나흘씩
And four days without sleeping.
연속 일한 적도 있었어
What kept me going was
the promise of meeting the girl...
내 여잘 만난다는
...who would be my wife.
신념 하나로 버텼지
Stick together, that's the way
it's gonna be.
우린 협력자야
-The way it was, and the way it will be.
-Mr. Calloway, sir?
- 앞으로도 계속
- 칼로웨이 씨?
lt's been a month today.
오늘이 한달짼데요
This girl, the love of your life...
자네 인생의 사랑이...
가장 좋아하는 꽃은
황수선화라네
...her favorite flowers are daffodils.
- 그것들을 가져다가...
- 황수선화
-So get that stuff....
-Daffodils.
The Lord is my shepherd,
l shall not be in want.
Daffodils.
황수선화
He makes me to lie down
in green pastures.
Daffodils.
He leads me beside the quiet waters.
황수선화
He restores my soul.
He guides me in the paths of
righteousness for his name's sake.
True to his word...
그는
Yea, though l walk through
the valley of the shadow of death...
...every month Amos would tell me
something new...
내 꿈의 여인에 관한 것들을
...about the woman of my dreams.
한 달에 하나씩 얘기해줬지
...l will fear no evil,
for you are with me.
Enjoy yourselves, enjoy yourselves.
즐거운 시간 되세요!
Surely goodness and love will
follow me all the days of my life.
She's going to college.
대학에 갈 거야
College. She's going to college.
대학, 그녀가 대학에 간다
She likes music.
음악을 좋아해
Music. She likes music.
음악, 그녀는 음악을 좋아해
Over the months, I learned a lot
about the woman I would marry...
몇 달간 꽤 많은 정보를
얻었지만
Over the months, I learned a lot
about the woman I would marry...
정작 이름이나 주소는
알 수 없었다
...but not her name,
and not where to find her.
That time had come.
I couldn't wait any longer.
드디어 때가 됐지
더이상 기다릴 수가 없었어
Have you ever heard a joke so many
times you've forgotten why it's funny?
Mr. Calloway?
칼로웨이 씨?
And then you hear it again
and suddenly it's new.
lt's Edward Bloom.
l need to talk to you.
드릴 말씀이 있는데요
You remember why you loved it
in the first place.
So he said he'll fight the giant
who was 15 feet tall!
Mr. Calloway?
칼로웨이 씨?
-No way!
-Dad! That's right, isn't it?
Pretty much.
See? So he was a giant.
That was my father's final joke,
I guess.
A man tells his stories so many times
that he becomes the stories.
They live on after him.
And in that way,
he becomes immortal.
No. Wait!
안 돼요!
That night, I discovered that most
things you consider evil or wicked...
보통 악마라 불리는 것들의
대개가
...are simply lonely and lacking
in social niceties.
실은 외롭고 약한 존재더구나
Didn't kill anything, did l?
나 아무 것도 안 죽였지?
A few rabbits. But l think one of them
was already dead.
토끼 몇 마리요
하난 이미 죽어있었구요
That would explain the indigestion.
그래서 소화가 안되는거군
고맙네
Thank you.
내가 잘못 생각했어
l was wrong about you, kid.
You may not have much,
but what you got, you got a lot of.
자네가 가진 건
적지만 대단한 거야
You could get any girl.
여자들도 좋아할 걸
There's only one l want.
한 명이면 돼요
Her name...
그 여잔...
...is Sandra Templeton.
산드라 탬플턴이야
She goes to Auburn.
어번 대학에 다녀
Semester's almost over,
so you better hurry.
학기가 끝나가니까
서두르는 게 좋을 거야
Thank you. Thank you.
감사합니다
-Good luck, kid!
-Thank you, sir!
- 잘해봐!
- 감사합니다!
-Bye, now.
-Bye, Edward.
안녕!
After saying my goodbyes,
I hopped three trains...
난 그날 오후로
어번에 닿기 위해
...to get to Auburn that afternoon.
기차를 세 번이나 탔단다
You don't know me,
but my name is Edward Bloom...
절 모르겠지만
이름은 에드워드고
...and l love you.
당신을 사랑합니다
l've spent the last three years
working to find out who you are.
당신을 찾으려고
3년이나 일했어요
l've been shot, stabbed, and trampled
a few times. l broke my ribs twice.
밟히고, 맞고,
부러지기까지 했죠
But it's all been worth it
to see you here now...
하지만 이렇게 만나고보니
...and to finally get to talk to you.
그럴만한 가치가 있었네요
Because l'm destined to marry you.
우린 결혼할 운명이거든요
l knew it when l saw you at the circus,
and l know it now more than ever.
처음 본 순간 알았지만
지금 더욱 확실해졌어요
-l'm sorry.
-You don't have to apologize to me.
- 미안해요
- 사과하지 마세요
l'm the luckiest person
you'll find today.
전 오늘 최고의 행운아예요
No, l'm sorry l'm engaged
to be married.
아뇨, 전 약혼자가 있어요
But you're wrong. l do know you.
하지만 당신에 관해선
잘 알아요
At least by reputation.
명성이 높더군요
Edward Bloom from Ashton.
애쉬톤의 에드워드 블룸
See, l'm actually engaged
to a boy from Ashton. Don Price.
제 약혼자도 거기 출신이에요
돈 프라이스
He was a few years older than you.
당신보다 두세살 많죠
그럼...
축하해요
괴롭혀서 미안해요
그만해! 뭐가 우스워!
안됐어
운명은 잔인하게
주위를 맴돈단다
애쉬톤을 떠나 만난 여자가
애쉬톤 최고의 멍청이랑
약혼했다니
싸울 때가 있으면
질 때가 있고
그걸 인정해야
할 때도 있는데
바보들만은
멈출 줄을 모르지
사실 난 늘 바보였단다
산드라 탬플턴...
당신이랑 결혼할거요!
이 규칙들을
일상에 적용해보면
훨씬 이해가 잘될겁니다
다음 그래프를 봅시다
사랑해, 산드라
- 황수선화!
- 좋아한다길래
다 어디서 났어요?
다섯개 주에 전화했어요
내가 결혼할 유일한
방법이라고 했죠
날 모르잖아요
이제부터 알면 돼요
산드라!
싸우지 않겠다고 약속해요
당신이 원한다면, 맹세하죠
- 블룸?
- 돈
여기서 뭐하는거야?
이 여잔 내 여자야!
애인이 있는 줄은 몰랐어
왜? 무서워서
못 싸우겠어?
안 싸운다고 약속했어
그만!
돈, 그만해!
평생 맞을 매를 다 맞았지만
결국 진건 돈이었단다
그런 과격한 행동이
심장병을 악화시켰지
그 녀석은 원래
심장이 약했거든
돈! 너랑 결혼 안해
이놈을 사랑해?
낯설지만 너보단 좋아
어쨌든 산드라의 결혼
날짜는 지켜졌단다
신랑이 바뀌었을 뿐이지
따로 결혼식을 하진
않으셨다면서요
준비는 해놨는데
복잡한 일이 있었어
갈증나게 만드는 약인가요?
난 평생 목이 말랐단다
왜 그랬는지 몰라
한번은 내가 열한살 때...
결혼식 얘기 중이에요
나도 안다
잠깐 옆길로 샜을 뿐이야
사람들은 대부분 일관되게
얘길 하지
복잡하진 않겠지만
재밌지도 않잖니
아버님 얘기가 좋아요
난 네가 좋다
서커스 사람들한텐
일정한 주소가 없다
나도 못 받는
우편물들이 많았지
그런데 병원에 있는 동안
우체국장이 날 찾아낸거야
내 심장은 산드라 것이었어도
내 몸만은 미국 정부에
속해있더구나
징집 명령서
병역 기간은 3년이었어
산드라를 만나는데
3년 걸렸는데
이제 와서 또 3년을
기다릴 순 없었지
난 복무기간을
일년 이내로 줄이기 위해
위험한 임무만
도맡아 했단다
웡 카이 탕 발전소에서
설계도를 훔치란
비밀 임무도
기꺼이 수락했지
당신들도 부족한게 있나요?
어떻게 시작을 놓쳐?
넌 날 혼자 두고
바보처럼 만들었어
넌 혼자가 아니잖아!
누구야?
해칠 생각 없어요
못 해치지
경비원!
방해하지 말아요!
커튼도 닫고!
제발 나 좀 도와줘요
우리가 왜요?
난 산드라에 대한 내 사랑과
지금의 시련에 대해
설명해줬단다
내 사랑은 늘...
내 구세주였고
그게 사랑의 운명이었지
우린 포경선을 타고
러시아로 가서
화물선을 타고 쿠바로
거기서 카누를 타고
마이애미로 가는
위험천만한 계획을 세웠다
우린 미국에서 뭘 하죠?
걱정 말아요
공연계 거물을
소개시켜 줄게요
밥 호프?!
더 거물요
준비됐죠?
그래서 우린
지구의 절반을 도는
힘든 여행을 시작했지
불행히도 미국에
연락할 길은 없었어
그러니 군에선
죽었다고 생각할밖에
안 돼!
산드란 넉달후에야
진정할 수 있었단다
전화벨이 울려도
기대하지 않았고
차가 지나가도
창밖을 보지 않았지
두분이 어떻게
만나셨는지 들었어
자긴 그런 얘기 안 해주더라
어번에서 만나셨어
자세한 내막은?
어떻게 사랑했는지
서커스나 전쟁같은거
아무 것도
얘기 안 해줬잖아
사실이 아니니까
그래도 로맨틱해
- 뭐?
- 프랑스 여자랑은...
로맨스를 논하는 게 아니래
아버질 사랑해?
아버진 호감을 주는 사람이야
사랑하냐구
당신이 이해해
아버진 집에 없는 시간이
더 많았어
어디선가 다른 삶을 살거란
생각도 했지
다른 가족, 다른 집
우릴 떠나서
그들에게 갈거라는
아니면...
가족 자체를
원치 않으셨던가
아무튼 아버진 이 지루한 곳을
견딜 수가 없어
얘길 만드시는 거야
- 그건 진실이 아냐
- 진실이 뭔데?
아버지한텐 들어본 적 없어
당신은...
아버질 좋아해
다들 좋아하지
아무튼 난 화난 게 아냐
알아
그러니까 아버지랑
얘기해야 돼
시보레는 고객들의
불만을 접수중입니다
GM 자동차에 대한
보상을 실시합니다
정가의 40%까지
절약할 수 있습니다
- 내가 그 얘기...
- 네
단풍나무랑 뷰익 얘기
들었어요
안들은 사람도 있어
나무가 차로 쓰러져
수액이 흘렀는데
그것 때문에
파리들이 달라붙었죠
그리곤 차를 들고 날아갔고요
진짜 얘긴
그 차를 어떻게 얻었는가야
- 그건...
- 아버지
그래
얘기 좀 해요
난 설거지나 해야겠다
도와드릴께요
- 빙산에 관해 아세요?
- 아냐고?
사람들이 식수로 쓰려고
텍사스까지
끌고 왔던 적이 있었지
그 안에 코끼리가
들어있는줄도 모르고
- 맘모스 종류였어
- 아버지!
뭐냐?
전 비유를 하려는 거예요
그럼 빙산을 아냐고
물어보지 말았어야지
사람은 질문을 하면
대답하게 되는거란다
알았어요...
빙산은 10%만 보여요
나머지 90%는 물밑에 있죠
아버지 얘기도...
마찬가지예요
저한텐 물위에 있는
작은 부분만 보여요
내 코있는데까지?
내 턱은?
전 아버지가
누군지 모르겠어요
한가지도 사실을
말하신 적이 없잖아요
천가진 말했을 거다
그게 내 일이잖니!
거짓말만...
재밌는 거짓말만
해 주셨죠
그런건 어린 아들이
침대맡에서 듣는거지
그 아들이 어른이 되도록
계속되는 신화가 아녜요
그래도 믿었어요
너무나 오래 아버지
얘길 믿었기에
모든게 사실이 아니란걸
알았을 땐
바보가 된 기분이었죠
아버진 산타같아요
매력적이지만 가짜인
사기꾼이라고 생각하는구나
그게 제가 봐온 전부니까요
아버지...
저한테도
아이가 생겨요
그 애가 절 이해 못한다면
전 절망 할 거예요
절망한다고?
그래서? 내가
어떤 사람이길 원하니?
그냥 아버지 자신요
좋든 나쁘든 어떻든간에요
난 평생 내가
아닌적이 없었다
다른 내가 있다면
그건 잘못 본거야!
아버지가 사무실이
필요하시데
집안에 만들면 괜찮을 거야
사실...
뭐가 중요한진
네가 더 잘 알잖니
뭐예요?
전쟁 중에 받은거야
다들 아버지가 죽은 줄 알았지
그게 사실이었어요?
아버지 얘기 전부가
거짓은 아니란다
어떠신지 보고 오마
난 좀 누워 있을께
그래
전쟁이 끝나자
다들 일을 찾기 시작했다
사망 기록이 있던 난
남들보다 불리했지만
별 기대없이 시작한
외판 일이 의외로 괜찮았다
어쨌든 난 누구나 인정하는
사교적인 사람이었으니까
- 축하하네
- 감사합니다
난 흰 울타리가 쳐진
집을 사기 위해
몇 주씩 출장을 갔고
그렇게 번 돈 전부를
은행에 저축했다
소개드릴 신제품
만능손입니다
난 계속 새로운 상품을
추가시켰고
내 영역은 텍사스 서부에까지
이르게 됐다
에드워드?
에드워드 블룸!
노더 윈슬로우요
세상에
난 여기서까지
그를 만나게 돼
깜짝 놀랐다
자네가 떠난 후
현실을 깨달았지
내가 모르는 삶이 있더군
여행을 시작했네
프랑스, 아프리카, 남미까지
매일 모험 하나씩
그게 내 모토야
멋지군요
여긴 웬일이세요?
오늘의 모험일세
전부 엎드려!
이쪽으로 밀어
- 잡아주겠나?
- 뭐?
총
난 현금 서랍을 비울거고
내 동료는
금고실을 맡을거다
당신이 도와줘
가!
죄송해요
해치지 않을테니
걱정 마세요
그래서 우는 거 아녜요
그냥...
돈이 없어서요
완전히 파산했거든요
비밀로 해주세요
그 저축 대부 조합은
이미 그 지역
부동산 투기꾼들한테
몽땅 털려 있었다
가세!
노더!
이것만 4백이야!
전부 서랍에서 나왔어
금고는?
뭐야? 그게 다야?
그렇네요
에드워드 블룸
자네 예금 증서군
빈손으로 갈 순 없잖아요
노더, 그 조합이 파산하건...
난 노더에게, 오일 머니와
그게 부동산 가격에
미치는 영향
그리고 허술한 신용 대출이
저축 대부 조합을
어떻게 부실하게 만드는지
설명해줬다
얘길 듣고 노더는
한가지 결론을 내렸다
월 가로 가겠네
거긴 돈이 모이는 곳이야
내 범죄 행각의 끝이 그에겐...
도와줘서 고맙네!
본격적인 시작이었다
그는 백만 불을 번 후
직업 상담에 대한
사례금이라며
내게 만 달러를 보내왔다
그 돈으로 아낸
흰 울타리가 쳐진
집을 살 수 있었고
그건 원하는 부를
다 얻었단 의미였다
물이 필요해
알아요
꽃에 물 주듯
당신한테도 가끔씩
물 좀 줘야겠어요
울지마
난 물 마를 날이 없을 거예요
신탁증서
에드워드는 제니퍼에게
3124번지를 신탁한다
유령 마을
3124번지
계속 쳐라, 잠깐만
안녕하세요
- 제니퍼 부인이신가요?
- 그래
윌이구나
사진을 봤지, 그래서 알아
케니, 오늘은 그만 하자
다음주에 와
엄마한테 돌려드려요?
안 드려도 말 안해
어떻게 만나셨죠?
여기도 판매 지역 중
하나였으니까
모두가 알았어
불륜이셨나요?
그렇게 직접적으로 말하다니
한 30분은 돌리다
말할 줄 알았는데
아버지가 여자들이랑
계신걸 봐왔으니까요
증거가 없었을 뿐
전 아버지가...
어머닐 속였다고 생각해요
하나 물어볼까?
왜 에디한테 직접
확인하지 않았지?
아버진 죽어가세요
네가 얼마나 알고 싶어
하는지 모르겠다만
지금의 네 아버질
부정할 필요는 없어
그것도 이렇게 뒤늦게
아버지한텐 거짓도 많지만
말씀안한 진실도
분명 많을 거예요
전 그 두 가질
화해시키고 싶어요
분명한 건 네 아버진
여기 정착할 생각이
없으셨단 거야
하긴 했었지
두 번
처음엔 너무 빨랐고
두 번짼 너무 늦었어
네 아버진 혼자 일했단다
그래도 다행히 누구나 인정하는
사교적인 사람이었던 터라
다들 그를 좋아했지
그러던 어느 날
출장에서 돌아오는 길에
평생 처음 보는
큰 폭우를 만났어
운명은 늘 주위를 맴돌면서
사람을 놀래킨단다
사람은 시절에 따라
사물을 다르게 보지
나이든 아버지 눈엔
여기도 달라보였어
새로운 길이 마을을
외부와 연결시켰고
은행, 빚 같은 것도
함께 들어왔다
마을 전체가 파산해버렸지
마을을 살리기 위한
경매가 열리겠습니다
- 시작가는 만 달러...
- 에드워드는
- 마을을 사기로 결심했단다
- 5만!
- 도저히 안 믿겨...
- 부자는 아니었지만
자기가 부자로 만들어준
이들에게 도움을 요청했지
- 도와 줘야 할...
- 대부분이 여길
와본 적도 없는
사람들이었지만
에드워드는 그들에게
자신의 꿈을 팔았다
그렇게 해서 농장을 사고
집과 가게들을 사들였지
뭘 사든 사람들을 내몰거나
세를 받는 일없이
하던 일을 계속 하게 했어
그렇게 하나하나
마을을 살려나간거야
여섯달 동안
그는 한군데만 제외하고
마을 전체를 다 샀단다
에드워드 블룸 씨군요
어떻게 알았죠?
원래 아무도 안오는데다
당신 말곤
올 사람이 없으니까요
마을을 사고 있잖아요
그래서 조사해 봤는데
여긴 고칠데가 많더군요
마을을 보존하려면
모든 집을 사들여야 돼요
들었어요
값도 잘 쳐드릴거고
이사할 필요도 없어요
명의 말곤 변하는게
아무 것도 없으니까
정확하게 말해주세요
여길 팔고도
계속 있을 수 있다구요?
주인은 당신인데
여전히 내꺼라구요?
난 여기 있고 당신은
원할 때마다 오가고요
제 말이 맞나요?
기본적으론 그렇죠
그럼 전 싫어요
변하는게 없다면
원래 변화없던
지금처럼 살겠어요
손해볼 일 아녜요
사람들한테 물어봐요
왜 하필 땅이죠?
중년의 위긴가요?
컨버터블 대신
마을을 사는 거예요?
사람들을 돕는게 행복해요
당신 행복엔 관심 없어요
- 미안해요, 기분 나빴나요?
- 아뇨
당신은 약속을 지켰어요
돌아왔죠
생각 보단 늦었지만
비멘 씨 딸이군요
성이 달라졌는데
결혼했나요?
전 18, 그는 28이었죠
그건 큰 차이더라구요
이 집은 안 팔겠어요, 블룸 씨
알겠습니다
시간 내줘서 고마워요
- 걸렸어요
- 네
- 미안해요!
- 괜찮아요, 놔두세요
- 아뇨, 제가...
- 그냥 가세요
- 하지만...
- 가요
대부분의 남자들은
실패를 받아들이고 가버리지
하지만 에드워드는
달랐단다
정지!
둘이 성격은 딴판이었는데
다리는 하나였죠
예전 모습이라곤
찾아볼 수 없을 만큼
오두막의 많은 부분이
달라졌지
늘 새로운걸 창조 한다는게
즐거웠어요
쿠바에선 우쿨렐레와
하모니카만 쓰는
새로운 공연을
고안해내기도 했죠
그냥 놔둬도 돼요
안 돼요
이건 아녜요
이러지 말아요
내 잘못이에요, 내가...
난 아내를 사랑해요
알아요
죽는 날까지 나한테 여자는
아내밖에 없어요
행복한 여자네요
미안해요, 제니, 정말
잠깐만요!
권리양도 증서
어느 날
에드워드는 떠났고
다신 돌아오지 않았단다
사람들은
그 소녀가 마녀가 된데다
미쳤다고 했어
그녀는 스스로 전설적인
존재가 됐지
그리고 이 얘긴
다시 여기서 끝난다
아버지가 마녀를 만난건
어릴 때였어요
아버지 방식으로 생각해라
에디한테
여자는 둘 뿐이었어
네 어머니와
그 외 모든 사람들
내 사랑은...
절대 돌려받지 못할
사랑이란 걸 깨달았다
꿈을 꾼 거였지
이런 얘기까지 하다니
아뇨, 알고 싶었어요
감사합니다
나도 그 사람한테
너같은 존재가
되고 싶었지만
그건 불가능했단다
내가 그런 척 해도
그의 다른 삶에선 네가
진짜였거든
엄마?
조세핀?
윌!
무슨 일이야?
발작을 일으키셨어
어머니랑 박사님이 보고계셔
괜찮으실까?
제가 있을 순 없겠죠
제 말은 그러니까
제가 남편 옆에 있어야
할텐데
제가 있을께요
엄만 집에 가 계세요
- 그래도 될까요?
- 네
윌, 무슨 일 있으면...
전화할게요
- 뵙고 가실래요?
- 그래
넌 감상적인 얘기 같은거
안해 좋구나
듣지도 못하는 환자한테
얘기가 무슨 소용 있겠니?
그런건 좋아요
우린 절대 말 안 하니까요
아버지가 너 태어난 날
얘기 해주시든?
그 물고기 얘긴
천번도 더 들었어요
그거 말고
진짜 얘기 못 들었어?
네
그날 네 어머닌
오후 3시쯤 여기 오셨다
마침 아버지가
출장 중이어서 어느 이웃이
모시고 왔지
한 주 정도 빨랐지만
합병증 하나 없이
완벽한 출산이었어
네 아버진 미안해 하셨다
하지만 그땐 분만실까지
동행할 수 없던 시절이라
옆에 계셨어도
달라질건 없었을 거야
이게 네가 태어날 때 얘기다
재미없지?
물고기나 반지 같은 걸로
꾸며진 얘기와
그냥 진실 중
하나를 고르라면, 나라도
더 환상적인 쪽을
택했을 거야
내 생각은 그래
괜찮은 생각이네요
아버지?
간호사 부를까요?
뭐 드려요? 어떤거요?
물 드려요?
물 드실래요?
강...
강이요?
그게...어떻게 되는지
말해다오
뭐가요?
내가 어떻게 죽는지
그 유리 눈에서요?
전 몰라요
그 얘긴 안해주셨잖아요
알았어요, 해볼게요
어떻게 시작하는지만
말 해 주세요
이렇게
알았어요
아버지랑 병원에 있는데
전 잠들어 있어요
그러다 일어나서
아버질 보니
좀 좋아지신 것 같았죠
아버지?
달라 보였어요
- 아버지?
- 나가자
제가 말해요
움직이시면 안 돼요
휠체어 가져와
시간 없어!
여기만 나가면 괜찮을 거야
우린 휠체어로...
- 빨리!
- 도망치고 있어요
뭐하는거냐?
박사님이 막으려고 해요
- 경비! 막아요!
- 잡역부들이
쫓아오고 있어요
엄마랑 조세핀도 있구요
저 사람들 좀 막아!
거길 나오니 아버지의
빨간 차가 있는데
그건 신제품이었어요
아버질 들었지만
웬일인지
무게가 안 느껴져요
그건 필요 없어!
난 물이 필요해
- 어디로 갈까요?
- 그 강
우린 교회로 가는
느린 차량들을 피해
글렌빌로 향해요
그리고 나서
강에 가까워져보니...
온다!
많은 사람들이 와있는 거예요
그러니까...
모두가요
믿을 수가 없어요
내 인생 얘기란다
다들 슬픈 기색 하나 없이
그저 만난걸 기뻐하며
작별 인사를 해요
안녕, 모두들!
잘 있어요! 안녕!
강에 있는 내 여인
아버진 원래 모습이 돼요
아주 큰 물고기요
그렇게 돌아가세요
그래...
정확하구나
엄마?
주는 나의 목자
아쉬울 것 없노라
그가 나를 푸른 초장에
누이시며
쉴만한 물 가로
인도 하시는도다
내 영혼을 소생시키시고
자기 이름을 위하여
의의 길로 인도하시는도다
내가 사망의 음침한
골짜기로 다닐지라도
해를 두려워 하지 않을 것은
주께서 나와 함께 하심이라
나의 평생에 선하심과 인자하심이
정녕 나를 따르리니...
너무 많이 들어
더는 웃기지 않은 농담이
다시 들으면
갑자기 새로워질 때가 있다
왜 웃었는지도 생각나고
우리 할아버진
거인이랑 싸울거랬어
- 말도 안 돼!
- 아빠, 내 말 맞죠?
당연하지
들었지? 거인이라니까
아버지의 농담은 이렇게 끝난다
그 자신이 이야기가 된
한 남자가 있다
그는 사후에도...
이야기로 남아, 불멸이 되었다